{
  "title": "Computer_Organization - Computer_Organization — Slot 24 (10 Questions)",
  "duration": 28,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Computer_Organization — Slot 24",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:<br>\nBit-slice processors <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1992)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>can be cascaded to get any desired word length processor</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>speed of operation is independent of the word length configured</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>do not contain anything equivalent of program counter in a 'normal' microprocessor</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Contain only the data path of a 'normal' CPU</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>can be cascaded to get any desired word length processor</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "It's Out of Syllabus now.<br><a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/557/gate1992-02-iii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:<br>The ALE line of  an 8085 microprocessor is used to: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1991)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Latch the output of an I/O instruction into an external latch.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Deactivate the chip-select signal from memory devices.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Latch the 8 bits of address lines AD7-AD0 into  an external latch.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Find the interrupt enable status of the TRAP interrupt.</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Latch the 8 bits of address lines AD7-AD0 into  an external latch.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/520/gate1991-03-v\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:\n<br>\nThe TRAP interrupts mechanism of the 8085 microprocessor: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1991)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>executes an RST by hardware</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>executes an instruction supplied by an external device through the INTA signal</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>executes an instruction from memory location 20H</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>executes a NOP</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/518/gate1991-03-iv\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:\n<br>The advantages of CMOS technology over a MOS is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1991)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>lower power dissipation</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>greater speed</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>smaller chip size</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>fewer masks for fabrication</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>greater speed</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/515/gate1991-03-i\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>On receiving an interrupt from a I/O device the CPU: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Halts for a predetermined time.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Hands over control of address bus and data bus to the interrupting device.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Branches off to the interrupt service routine immediately.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Branches off to the interrupt service routine after completion of the current instruction.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Branches off to the interrupt service routine after completion of the current instruction.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/80274/gate1987-1-viii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>A microprogrammed control unit <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Is faster than a hard-wired control unit.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Facilitates easy implementation of new instruction.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Is useful when very small programs are to be run.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Usually refers to the control unit of a microprocessor.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Facilitates easy implementation of new instruction.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/80199/gate1987-1-vi\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>The most relevant addressing mode to write position-independent codes is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Direct mode</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Indirect mode</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Relative mode</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Indexed mode</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Relative mode</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/80194/gate1987-1-v\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Microprogrammed control unit: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>is faster than a hardwired control unit</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>facilitates easy implementation of new instructions</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>is useful when very small programs are to be run</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>usually refers to control unit of a microprocessor</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>facilitates easy implementation of new instructions</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/166/gate1987-1-vi\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>The data transfer rate of a double-density floppy disk system is about: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>5K bits/sec</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>50K bits/sec</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>500K bits/sec</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>5000K bits/sec</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>500K bits/sec</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/80281/gate1987-1-x\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>The refreshing rate of dynamic RAMs is in the range of <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2 microseconds</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2 milliseconds.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>50 milli seconds</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>500 milliseconds</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>2 milliseconds.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/80278/gate1987-1-ix\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}